Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements Collection, 1900-2004 and undated, bulk 1965-1990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements collection 1900-2004 and undated, bulk 1965-1990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company.
40 linear feet Extent: 18,000 Items
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), founded in 1864, is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the world. It opened its first international office in London in 1899, and by 1930 the agency had established offices in some 30 countries. At present, JWT manages offices or partnership arrangements in approximately 90 countries. The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) International Advertisements Collection spans the years 1900-2004 and consists primarily of print advertisements, along with some transparencies, photocopies of advertising, and other collateral material that document some of JWT's international advertising campaigns through the 20th century. Clients include a variety of local, national and multinational commercial firms, as well as government institutions and public service organizations. The holdings of the collection are uneven, with the bulk of the advertisements dating from the mid-1960s up to about 1990. There are limited early advertisements from Chesebrough-Pond's, General Motors, and other clients dating from the late 1920s and early 1930s in print and on microfilm from the various offices established during those years. There are almost no international advertisements from roughly 1933 to the middle of the 1950s. The United Kingdom, the British Commonwealth countries, and Latin America account for most of the advertisements from the mid-1950s to the late 1970s. While the holdings since about 1980 are much larger than earlier holdings, they are by no means complete, and vary substantially from office to office. Key multinational clients represented in the collection include Chesebrough-Pond's, Eastman Kodak, Ford, General Motors, Kraft, IBM, Pepsi, R.J. Reynolds, and Unilever. English translations of foreign-language advertisements are often provided by JWT's Asian and Pacific Offices. European and Latin American Offices provided translations far less frequently. Advertisements for members of the British Commonwealth are generally available in English only or in both English and the local language. Spanish-language advertisements produced by JWT offices in the United States, intended for the domestic Spanish-speaking population as well as for Latin America, may be found in the J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertisements Collection.
RL.00715
Language: Material in English, Dutch, French, German, Italian, Spanish, Chinese, Hindi, Japanese, Thai
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 1994, with additions in subsequent years.
Historical Note: Dates JWT International Offices Opened
AFRICA
Egypt: Alexandria, 1927
South Africa: Cape Town, 1930
South Africa: Johannesburg/Sandton, 1932
South Africa: Port Elizabeth, 1928
ASIA/PACIFIC
Australia: Brisbane, 1984
Australia: Melbourne, 1929-1934, 1937
Australia: Perth, 1984
Australia: Sydney, 1929
Hong Kong, 1977
India: Bangalore, 1958-1959, 1979
India: Bombay, 1929
India: Calcutta, 1934
India: Madras, 1955
India: New Delhi, 1944
Indonesia: Jakarta, 1930, 1982
Japan: Osaka, 1931, 1957
Japan: Tokyo, 1956
Malaysia: Kuala Lumpur, 1975
New Zealand: Aukland, 1976
New Zealand: Wellington, 1930, 1974
Philippines: Manila, 1956
Singapore, 1978
Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1956, 1981
Taiwan: Taipei, 1983
Thailand: Bangkok, 1983
CANADA
Montreal, 1929
Toronto, 1911-1916, 1930
Vancouver, 1958
EUROPE
Austria: Vienna, 1930, 1960
Belgium: Antwerp, 1927
Belgium: Brussels, 1930, 1958
Denmark: Copenhagen, 1927, 1967
Finland: Helsinki, 1985
France: Paris, 1927-1940, 1949
Germany: Berlin, 1927
Germany: Düsseldorf, 1983
Germany: Frankfurt, 1952
Germany: Hamburg, 1983
Greece: Athens, 1974
Italy: Milan, 1951
Italy: Rome, 1962
Netherlands: Amsterdam, 1957
Netherlands: The Hague, 1928
Norway: Oslo, 1985
Poland: Warsaw, 1929
Portugal: Lisbon, 1929, 1967, 1973, 1981
Romania: Bucharest, 1929
Slovenia: 1993
Spain: Barcelona, 1932, 1966
Spain: Madrid, 1927, 1966
Sweden: Stockholm, 1927, 1969
Switzerland: Zug, 1964
Switzerland: Zurich, 1965
Turkey: Istanbul, 1930, 1985
United Kingdom: London, 1899-1916, 1919
United Kingdom: Manchester, 1980
LATIN AMERICA
Argentina: Buenos Aires, 1929
Bolivia: La Paz, 1978
Brazil: Rio de Janeiro, 1931
Brazil: São Paulo, 1929
Chile: Santiago, 1929, 1944
Colombia: Bogotá, 1944
Ecuador: Guayaquil, 1982
Ecuador: Quito, 1982
Mexico: Mexico City, 1943
Panama: Panama City, 1955
Puerto Rico: San Juan, 1955-1978
Uruguay: Montevideo, 1929
Venezuela: Caracas, 1955, 1964
Since the J. Walter Thompson Company opened its first international office in London in 1899, the agency has grown into a multinational company with offices in dozens of countries on every inhabited continent. To the general public, the most visible form of the agency’s presence around the globe has been the advertisements themselves. In some cases, advertisements for the products of multinational corporations such as Eastman-Kodak, IBM, Kraft, Pepsico, R.J. Reynolds, and Unilever reflect the spread of American commercial culture and economic influence across the globe. Other advertisements promote local products, organizations, or public service campaigns. Whatever the subject matter, the advertisements usually reflect the synthesis of American and international advertising with local culture and fashions.
Collection Overview
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) International Advertisements Collection spans the years 1900-2004 and consists primarily of print advertisements, along with some transparencies, photocopies of advertising, and other collateral material that document some of JWT's international advertising campaigns through the 20th century. Clients include a variety of local, national and multinational commercial firms, as well as government institutions and public service organizations. The holdings of the collection are uneven, with the bulk of the advertisements dating from the mid-1960s up to about 1990. There are limited early advertisements from Chesebrough-Pond's, General Motors, and other clients dating from the late 1920s and early 1930s in print and on microfilm from the various offices established during those years. A larger selection of early advertisements may be found on Microfilm Reel #41 (35 mm). Contact Reference Staff for access.
There are almost no international advertisements from roughly 1933 to the middle of the 1950s. The United Kingdom, the British Commonwealth countries, and Latin America account for most of the advertisements from the mid-1950s to the late 1970s. While the holdings since about 1980 are much larger than earlier holdings, they are by no means complete, and vary substantially from office to office. Key multinational clients represented in the collection include Chesebrough-Pond's, Eastman Kodak, Ford, General Motors, Kraft, IBM, Pepsi, R.J. Reynolds, and Unilever.
English translations of foreign-language advertisements are often provided by JWT's Asian and Pacific Offices. European and Latin American Offices provided translations far less frequently. Advertisements for members of the British Commonwealth are generally available in English only or in both English and the local language. Spanish-language advertisements produced by JWT offices in the United States, intended for the domestic Spanish-speaking population as well as for Latin America, may be found in the Domestic Advertisements Collection.
The collection is organized into the following geographical series: Africa, Asia/Pacific, Canada, Europe, and Latin America. The multinational series are arranged alphabetically by country. For countries with multiple offices, the folders are arranged alphabetically by the office of origin. When it has been determined that more than one office within a country has been responsible for a client, the advertisements for that client are housed at the beginning of the country’s collection in a Multiple Office group, listed alphabetically by product and the office involved as applicable (for exception, see below).
Advertisements are arranged according to the parent company of the product being marketed (i.e. Miracle Whip, Philadelphia cream cheese, Miracoli pasta and tomato sauce, and various salad dressings are all filed together under Kraft, within a given country). Because of corporate buyouts and name changes, it may be useful to search for a product under an older or more recent parent company (for example, Standard Brands and Nabisco, or Unilever and Brooke Bond Oxo). In some cases, the parent company may not be as well known as the brand name (such as Reckitt and Colman, parent company of Gerber Baby Foods), or could not be determined, so some flexibility in searching for products and companies is recommended.
The collection of advertisements from the Montreal Office is an exception to some of the notes and guidelines above. With 28 boxes of advertisements in French and English spanning 1921 to the 1990s, the Montreal Office Subseries is almost as large as the remainder of the entire collection. To maintain the integrity of these holdings, all advertisements from JWT/Montreal are housed together in the Montreal Office Subseries, even when Toronto and/or Vancouver also produced advertisements for the same client (for example, Labatts).
In addition, a small collection of international advertisements, mounted on foamboard for display purposes, is itemized at the end of this finding aid under the heading Mounted Advertisements.
Large-format materials have been removed to Oversize Materials. A dummy folder indicated by text in brackets has been inserted at the logical location of the removed material.
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; Advertisements; Advertising -- Africa; Advertising -- Asia; Advertising -- Australia; Advertising -- Canada; Advertising -- Europe; Advertising -- European Union Countries; Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising -- Brand name products; Advertising -- History; Advertising -- India; Advertising -- Latin America; Advertising, Public service; Chesebrough-Pond's.; Advertising campaigns; Brand name products -- Marketing; International business enterprises; Eastman Kodak Company; Ford Motor Company; General Motors Corporation; International Business Machines Corporation; Kraft Foods Company; PepsiCo, Inc.; R.J. Reynolds Industries; Unilever (Firm); Microfilm; Transparencies; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Additional materials relating to this collection may be found in other Hartman Center collections. Advertisements from German and European advertising campaigns may be found in the J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Advertisements Collection. Advertisements produced in the United States for use in international campaigns may be found in the J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements Collection.
Contents of Collection
- Africa Series, 1920s-1990 and undated
  Arranged alphabetically by country, then office name and product.
  Large-format materials have been removed to Oversize Materials. A dummy folder indicated by text in brackets has been inserted at the logical location of the removed material.
  - Egypt (Alexandria Office)
    - General Motors, circa 1920s (from microfilm) (Box AF1)
  - Nigeria (Lagos Office) (Box AF1)
    - Eastman Kodak, consumer advertisements, 1965 (Box AF1)
  - South Africa (Box AF1)
    - Capetown Office (Box AF1)
      - Campari, 1981, 1984, 1987 (Box AF1)
      - Costantia carpets, 1982 (Box AF1)
      - Gants canned fruit, 1985 (Box AF1)
      - Martell (V.O. brandy), 1984 (Box AF1)
      - Petz (Pamper) cat food, 1982, 1987 (Box AF1)
      - Safren (Box AF1)
        - Safcover computer back-up services, 1985 (Box AF1)
        - Safmarine shipping, 1985, 1987 (Box AF1)
      - Stellenbosch Farmers (See also Oversize Box OV1 and Oversize Folder OF1), (2 folders) (Box AF1)
        - Autumn Harvest wine, 1985 (Box AF1)
        - Cresta Blanca wine, undated (Box AF1)
        - Esprit fruit wine, 1987 (Box AF1)
        - La Vie wine, 1984 (Box AF1)
        - Lanzerac wine, 1984-1985 (Box AF1)
        - Mainstay cane spirits, 1974, 1981-1982 (Box AF1)
        - Tasheimer wines, 1974 (Box AF1)
        - Three Ships whiskey, 1978, 1984 (Box AF1)
        - Truman's apple ale, 1984 (Box AF1)
        - Wisla vodka, 1987 (Box AF1)
        - Zonnebloem wine, 1984, 1985 (Box AF1)
    - Johannesburg Office (Box AF1)
      - Barclays, 1974, 1980-1981 (See also Oversize Box OV1) (Box AF1)
      - Beecham/Dermacult, Ltd. (Box AF1)
        - Grand-Pa Honey and Menthol hot medication, circa 1980 (Box AF1)
        - Med-Lemon hot medication, 1977 (Box AF1)
        - Sally Hansen nail polish, 1982 (Box AF1)
        - Slim Shake, 1982 (Box AF1)
      - Eastman Kodak (Box AF1)
        - Developing services, 1982 (Box AF1)
        - Ektachrome/Kodachrome film, 1985, 1987 (Box AF1)
        - Ektalite 10 camera, circa 1980 (Box AF1)
        - Kodak Poly-Contrast paper, 1987 (Box AF1)
        - VR 35 camera, 1987 (Box AF1)
      - Ford (Sierra), 1988 (See also Oversize Box OV1) (Box AF1)
      - Grapetiser grape juice, 1987 (Box AF1)
      - ICL computers, with documentation, 1984-1985 (See also Oversize Box OV1) (Box AF1)
      - James Buchanan and Company (Black & White scotch whiskey), 1980-1982 (Box AF1)
      - Kellogg Company S.A. (Box AF1)
        - Rice Krispies, 1963 (Box AF1)
        - Various bran cereals, 1980, 1990 (Box AF1)
      - Kraft (See also Oversize Box OV1) (Box AF1)
        - Margarine, 1990 (Box AF1)
        - Miracle Whip, with documentation, 1985 (Box AF1)
        - Salad dressings, with documentation, 1985 (Box AF1)
      - MacDonald Green (Old Parr scotch whiskey), 1984 (Box AF1)
      - Marley flooring, 1982 (Box AF1)
      - Philips (Box AF1)
        - Kitchen Helper, 1980 (Box AF1)
        - Televisions, 1982 (Box AF1)
        - VHS video recorders, 1984 (Box AF1)
      - Roundtree Mackintosh (NUX) chocolate bars, 1963 (Box AF1)
      - Royal Beech Nut (Box AF1)
        - Bubble-Yum chewing gum, 1980 (Box AF1)
        - Super C candy, 1982 (Box AF1)
      - St. Christopher alcohol-free beer, 1984 (Box AF1)
      - Seiko, 1982 (See also Oversize Box OV1) (Box AF1)
      - Sylvachen (Sylvascen) sun protection pills, circa 1980, 1982 (Box AF1)
      - Tiger Oats National Milling Company (Star Foods), 1985 (Box AF1)
      - Unilever (See also Oversize Box OV1), (3 folders) (Box AF1)
        - Harmony, 1982-1983 (Box AF1)
        - Lipton SA (Box AF1)
          - Fray Bentos beefy spread, 1990 (Box AF1)
          - Pit Company tea, 1974, 1982, 1990 (Box AF1)
        - Lux soap, 1980, 1982, 1985 (Box AF1)
        - Mentadent, with documentation, 1985 (Box AF1)
        - Pears moisturizer, 1985 (Box AF1)
        - Riche hair conditioner, 1982 (Box AF1)
        - Second Debut lotion, undated (Box AF1)
      - Warner-Lambert (Trident chewing gum), 1990 (Box AF1)
      - Witatersrand Agricultural Society ( The Rand Show), 1982 (Box AF1)
    - Port Elizabeth Office (Box AF1)
      - Standard Brands (Royal baking powder), 1931-1932 (Box AF1)
        [See also Nabisco Brands in other countries]
    - Multiple Offices (Box AF1)
      - Booth's Gin (Capetown and Johannesburg Offices), 1981-1982 (Box AF1)
      - Reckitt-Coleman (Box AF1)
        - Dettol antiseptic, 1987 (Johannesburg Office) (Box AF1)
        - Dispirin analgesic, 1987 (Johannesburg Office) (Box AF1)
        - Gerber/Purity Junior juice (Capetown Office), 1987 (Box AF1)
    - Undetermined Office (Box AF1)
      - AMCHAM (American Chamber of Commerce in South Africa), 1986 (See also Oversize Box OV1) (Box AF1)
      - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1962 (Box AF1)
      - Citrus Exchange (Citrus Seal), 1982 (Box AF1)
      - Eastman Kodak, 1962, 1965-1967 (Box AF1)
      - Kraft (Miracle Whip), 1998 (Box AF1)
      - Schafft beer, circa 1980 (Box AF1)
      - Yardley of London cosmetics, 1974 (Box AF1)
      - [United Airlines: See Oversize Box OV1] (Box AF1)
- Asia/Pacific Series, 1920-2003 and undated (Box AF1)
  Arranged alphabetically by country, then office name and product. Contains advertisements, and documentation and negatives where noted. For geographic and thematic reasons, Australia and New Zealand are arranged at the end of the series.
  - Multinational Campaigns, Undetermined Office (Box AF1)
    - Chevron, 1996 (Box AP1)
    - Eastman Kodak, 1965-1969 (Box AP1)
    - Nike, 1997 and undated (Box AP1)
  - [Australia: See Box AP10] (Box AP1)
  - Hawai'i (pre-statehood) (Box AP1)
    - Chesebrough-Pond's (in Japanese), 1931 (Box AP1)
  - China (Box AP1)
    - Hong Kong Office (Box AP1)
      - [Agnes Long Wooten: See Oversize Box OV2] (Box AP1)
      - Alfa Romeo (Milan Motors/Finaziaria Meccanica), 1989 (See also Oversize Box OV2) (Box AP1)
      - Arctic Video/Video 7, 1989 (Box AP1)
      - British Railways Board (Mass Transit Railway Corp.), 1987, 1989-1990 (See also Oversize Box OV2) (Box AP1)
      - China Light and Power Company and Ltd., 1989 (Box AP1)
      - Citicorp (See also Oversize Box OV2), (2 folders) (Box AP1)
        - Citibank Services, 1981, 1989 (Box AP1)
        - Diner's Club, 1989, 1990 (Box AP1)
      - Club Med, 1984 (Box AP1)
      - Eastman Kodak (See also Oversize Box OV2) (Box AP1)
        - Consumer advertisements, 1961, 1964-1967 (Box AP1)
        - Kodacolor Gold film, 1987 (Box AP1)
        - Kodak paper, 1987, 1989 (Box AP1)
        - VR 35 camera, 1987, 1989 (Box AP1)
      - [Ford Motor Company: See Oversize Box OV2] (Box AP1)
      - Government Information Services (Water pollution campaign), 1990 (Box AP1)
      - GTE (Yellow Pages), 1990 (Box AP1)
      - Hyatt Hotels, 1984-1985, 1988 (Box AP1)
      - Hong Kong Carpet Manufacturers (Tai Ping), 1984 (Box AP1)
      - Hong Kong Telecom (Integrated Business Systems), 1988 (Box AP1)
      - Hong Kong Telephone fax/minilink services, 1990 (Box AP1)
      - Hong Kong Yuen real estate, 1987 (Box AP1)
      - IBM, 1984-1985, 1987-1990 (See also Oversize Box OV2, Oversize Folder OF1), (9 folders) (Box AP2)
      - International Herald Tribune, 1988-1989 (Box AP2)
      - International Wool Secretariat (China Division), 1985 (Box AP2)
      - Jade Animation Production, 1988 (Box AP3)
      - James Lang Wooton International Real Estate, 1989 (Box AP3)
      - J. Walter Thompson Company, 1988-1989 (Box AP3)
      - Kraft, 1997 (Box AP3)
      - Lazare Diamonds, 1988 (Box AP3)
      - Lufthansa (Box AP3)
        - German National Tourism Office, 1987 (Box AP3)
        - Lufthansa Passenger and Cargo Services, 1982, 1985, 1987 (Box AP3)
      - [Motorola: See Oversize Box OV2] (Box AP3)
      - Nestlé (Nescafé), 1989 (See also Oversize Box OV2) (Box AP3)
      - Pacific Link Communications Ltd. mobile phones, 1989 (Box AP3)
      - Pearl and Dean Advertising Agency, 1988-1989 (See also Oversize Box OV2) (Box AP3)
      - [PepsiCo: See Oversize Box OV2] (Box AP3)
      - Philips (Box AP3)
        - Microwave oven, 1989 (Box AP3)
        - Philishave, 1987 (Box AP3)
        - Space heater, 1988 (Box AP3)
      - Purolator Courier, 1985 (See also Oversize Box OV2) (Box AP3)
      - Red Cross, 1987 (Box AP3)
      - Reebok (Robert Stevens Holdings), 1984 (Box AP3)
      - Reuters Software, 1990 (Box AP3)
      - R.J. Reynolds (Salem), 1985, 1987-1989 (See also Oversize Box OV2) (Box AP3)
      - Royal Dutch Petroleum (Shell), 1989, (2 folders) (Box AP3)
      - [Scott Paper Company: See Oversize Folder OF2] (Box AP3)
      - Shangri-La Hotels (China World Trade Center Hotels, Beijing), 1990 (Box AP3)
      - Spanish Trade Commission, 1988 (Box AP3)
      - Standard Chartered Banks, 1987-1989 (See also Oversize Box OV2), (3 folders) (Box AP3)
      - The Swank Shop, 1990 (Box AP3)
      - Warner-Lambert (Box AP3)
        - Chiclets gum, 1990 (Box AP3)
        - Clorets breath mints, 1988 (Box AP3)
    - Shanghai Office (Box AP3)
      - De Beers, 1997 (Box AP3)
      - San Miguel beer, 1997 (Box AP3)
      - Valor beer, 1997 (Box AP3)
      - Ying Xiong, 1997 (Box AP3)
  - India (Box AP3)
    - Bangalore Office (Box AP3)
      - Bharat Electronics, 1990 (Box AP4)
      - Designer Pavings and Tile Pvt. Ltd., cobblestones, 1990 (Box AP4)
      - Ganjam Nagappa and Son Pvt. Ltd., jewelry, 1989 (Box AP4)
      - Hindustan Aeronautics Ltd., 1984 (Box AP4)
      - ITC Ltd. (Crystal groundnut oil), 1990 (Box AP4)
      - Smithkline Beecham (Eskamer, Eskayef Ltd.), 1990 (Box AP4)
      - Unilever/Brooke Bond India, Ltd. (Taj Mahal tea), 1985, 1990 (Box AP4)
      - Western Indian Vegetable Products (WIVPRO - WIPRO Products Ltd.), 1982, 1989 (Box AP4)
    - Bombay (Mumbai) Office (Box AP4)
      - Air India, 1982, 1984-1985, 1989-1990 (Box AP4)
      - Cadbury-Schweppes (Dollops ice cream), 1990 (Box AP4)
      - Citicorp, 1989 (Box AP4)
      - Colour Chemicals, dyes and pigments, 1984-1985 (Box AP4)
      - Eastman Kodak/India Photographic Company Ltd., 1985 (Box AP4)
      - F. Hoffman Laroche and Company (Roche vitamins), 1984 (Box AP4)
      - Godrej and Boyce Manufacturing Company Pvt. Ltd., refrigerators, 1989 (Box AP4)
      - Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Ltd. (Flint spray insecticide), 1990 (Box AP4)
      - Hindustan Thompson Associates, 60th anniversary campaign, with documentation, 1989-1990 (Box AP4)
      - Inacco Ltd. (Carara) flooring, with documentation, 1990 (Box AP4)
      - ITC Ltd. (Indian Heritage) agricultural exports, undated (Box AP4)
      - Kemco Chemicals (Borphis) antiseptic cream, with documentation, 1985 (Box AP4)
      - [Ministry of Health, Family Planning and Urban Development: See Oversize Box OV2] (Box AP4)
      - Nestlé (Sunrise) instant coffee, 1984 (Box AP4)
      - Philips, light bulbs and lamps, 1982, 1985 (Box AP4)
      - Seiko (Allwyn Quartz), 1982 (Box AP4)
      - Tomco (501) soap, 1920 (Box AP4)
      - Unilever (Lux) soap, 1982, 1984, 1990 (with documentation) (Box AP4)
      - W.H. Deeth Private Ltd. (Shayam Ahuja) textiles, 1982, 1984-1985 (with documentation) (Box AP4)
      - Wiltech India Ltd. (Wilman II and Wilzor razors), 1982 (Box AP4)
      - World War II posters, 1942 (Box AP4)
        [Includes explanatory essay by S.D. Khadlikar, an artist with JWT Bombay during the war years]
    - Calcutta Office (Box AP4)
      - ALCAN Aluminum (Indian Aluminum Company Ltd.), 1982 (Box AP4)
      - Bata India (Box AP4)
        - Canvas Shoe, 1990 (Box AP4)
        - North Star, 1985 (Box AP4)
      - British and American Tobacco (Box AP4)
        - Golf tournament, 1990 (Box AP4)
        - Olympic campaign, 1984 (Box AP4)
        - Willis cigarettes, 1984 (Box AP4)
      - C.K. Son and Company (Box AP4)
        - Basant Molati skin lotion, 1982 (Box AP4)
        - Jabakusum hair Oil, 1982 (Box AP4)
      - Dunlop Tires, 1982 (Box AP4)
      - G.D. Pharmaceuticals (Boroline) antiseptic, 1982, 1984 (Box AP4)
      - Gramophone Company of India, 1984 (Box AP4)
      - IEL Ltd./ICI Chemicals (Dulux Paints), 1989-1990 (Box AP4)
      - Kwality ice creams, 1990 (Box AP4)